不用害怕 孩子 会成功的
No need to be scared, son, this is gonna work.
回身吧
Now turn around.
不然会错过这么多年来你看到的第一次日出
You're about to miss your first sunrise in years.
爸爸
Dad!
皮特
Peter!
周末跟子女在一起做的最棒的事
亚瑟·K·洛根科学博物馆 - 哈勃展览
不好意思 冒昧打搅
Excuse me. I'm sorry to bother you,
要买盒饼干吗
but could I interest you in a box of cookies
你最喜欢哪种的啊
Which kind is your favorite
棉花糖味的
S'mores.
如果你妈妈同意的话
Then, if it's okay with your mom,
就给我来盒这种的 然后
I'll get a box of those, and...
你自己留着就好
you keep it for yourself.
你人真好 谢谢
That's very kind. Thank you.
还是四块吗
Still four dollars
现在五块了 你女儿多大了
Five, now. How old's your daughter
看你挺清楚以前多少钱的 所以我
You knew the old price, so I just--
给
Here you go.
该说什么呀
What do we say
感谢您的支持
Thank you for your support.
快点 我们要迟到了
Hustle up, we're gonna be late.
突发新闻
凯西·麦克唐纳
纽约中城
警方似乎无法解释
Police have seemingly no explanation
凶杀案激增的原因
for the surge in homicides.
曼哈顿市中心尤为明显
Nowhere is that more apparent than here in midtown Manhattan,
时代广场和宾夕法尼亚车站
where Times Square and Penn Station
在这场残酷屠杀之后
are eerily empty
几近空无一人
after a wave of brutal slayings.
你这是穿的什么啊
What are you wearing
很酷对不对
Pretty cool, right
看这个
And check it out.
暗兜
Secret pockets.
你能换件正常衣服吗
Can you go put on something normal
但我想穿这件
But I want to wear this.
我们聊过的 在家里
We have talked about in this house,
你想穿什么都行
you can wear whatever you want.
但出去外面
But out in the world--
可别人那样也不关我事啊
But why is it my fault if people act--
就是别那么引人注目
Just don't make yourself such an easy target.
抱歉 我不是说
I'm sorry. I-I didn't mean--
没事
No, it's fine.
我去换衣服
I'll just go change.
要帮忙吗
Oh, you need some help
不用了谢谢 我就住这儿
I'm good, thanks. This is me right here.
终于有人搬来隔壁了
Oh, so somebody's finally moving in next door.
我好了
Okay, I'm ready.
这是我儿子 以赛亚
This is my son, Isaiah.
我叫内奥米
I am Naomi.
以赛亚 这是咱们新邻居
Isaiah, this is our new neighbor.
马克
Mark.
很高兴见到你 马克先生
Nice to meet you, Mr. Mark.
他看起来人挺不错的哈
He seemed pretty nice, huh
他有什么问题吗
Okay, what's wrong with him
没有
Nothing.
别生气
Don't be pissed.
爸
Dad!
哥们儿 瞧瞧
Oh, man. Look at you.
长这么大啦 这是吃什么了
You got so big, and where did all of this come from, huh
嘿 我上回见你的时候
Hey, now, the last time I saw you,
你在练硬币魔术
you were working on a coin trick.
你用这个能变吗
Think you can do it with this
当然
Sure.
为什么上面写“三个月”啊
Why does it say, "Three Months"
算是一种奖励吧
Well, it's, uh, kind of an award.
-奖励  -看好了
- An award. - You watching
嗯
Yeah.
不是吧
Oh, come on now.
-怎么会  -以赛亚
- What. -Isaiah, give your dad
把“奖励”还给你爸 去车上等我
his "award" back and wait for me in the car.
你越来越厉害了 儿子
You're getting real good, son.
在你开口之前
Before you say anything--
你不能一直这样
You can't keep doing this.
你不能一直在他的生活里进进出出
You cannot keep popping in and out of his life.
我知道 所以我在彻底戒断之前
I know, I know. That is why I stayed away
不会离你们太近
- until I got some real sobriety.
我每天都会参加互助会
I've been going to meetings every day.
我不想再老生常谈了
I can't have this conversation again.
我找了份工 租了套公寓
I have a job, I have an apartment.
-现在说这太晚了  -我现在能当个真正的父亲了
- It's too late for this. - I-I can be a real father now.
要不我今晚过来吃饭
Look, maybe I can come over
证明给你们看
for dinner tonight and prove it.
你以为我会为你做饭是么
You think I'm gonna cook for your ass
要是没想好是你跟家做饭还是打包外卖
Well, if it's between your cooking and take-out,
我可以带点吃的过来
I'm happy to pick something up.
没必要特地给我做
You wouldn't be doing it for me.
以赛亚 麻烦坐后面去
Isaiah Put your little butt in the back seat, please.
好点了吗
Better
-你还好吧  -没事
- You okay. - Yeah.
小伤而已
It's barely a scratch.
我没事
I'm fine.
你觉得这个新地方怎么样
What do you think of the new place
你买了大电视
You got the big screen
对
Oh, yes.
你之前说太贵了
You said it was too expensive.
可你说很棒 所以
And you said it was awesome, so...
怎么了 艾莉
What's wrong Ellie
这些我们一样都带不走
Can't take any of it with us.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about
要是我们的收拾东西逃跑的话
If we have to pack up and run.
过来
Come here.
我给你看点东西 来
I'm gonna show you something. Come here.
浴室哎
Wow. A bathroom.
更正一下 备用浴室
Eh, correction. A spare bathroom.
注意到什么了没
You notice anything about it
没窗户
No windows.
There's no windows.
我有自己的房间了
I get my own room
这就是我们的家 艾莉
We're home now, Ellie.
接下来很长一段时间我们哪儿都不会去
And we're not going anywhere for a long time,
也就是说我们得比往常更加小心
which means we have to be even more careful than normal.
我很小心
I'm careful.
是 但你不大擅长融入社会
Yeah, well, you're not always great at blending in.
-擅长的  -你沾了点
- Yes, I am. - Mm, you've got a little...
我也得融入社会
I also have to blend in, okay
也就是说我得找到份合法工作
Which means I have to find a legitimate job.
这些箱子等我回来以后拆吧
And when I get back, I will tackle those boxes, okay
我可以拆的
I could do it.
是
Yeah, right.
这种宜家的东西 就像
This IKEA stuff, it's just like...
是个虐待狂造出来的拼图
a puzzle made by a...by a sadist.
我喜欢拼图
- I like puzzles. -
行吧
All right.
有事发信息给我 好吧
Text me if you need anything, okay
那男生多大了
How old was the boy...
住隔壁那个
who lives next door
不清楚 十一二岁吧
I don't know. Uh, 11, 12.
我是这么打算的 一会儿晚上我回来以后
Listen, I was thinking, when I get back later tonight,
咱们可以去时代广场转转
maybe we can go down to Times Square.
为什么
Ew. Why
有个新开的科学展
There's this new science exhibit.
他们展出了由哈勃望远镜拍出来的照片
They have photos from the Hubble.
你要不想去也没关系
But if you don't want to go, that's fine.
我没这么说 还开着吗
I didn't say that. Is it even open
什么意思 晚上还开是吗
What you mean? At night?
我是说 这么多起凶杀案
I mean, with all the murders going on.
怎么了 咱们来这儿不就是因为这个么
What? That's why we get to be here, right
什么情况
What do we got?
你见过这种情况吗
You ever seen anything like this
见过 跟我爸打猎的时候见过
Yeah. Hunting with my dad.
遇到一个被熊咬死的人
Came across a guy got mauled to death by a bear.
还真是段温馨的童年记忆呢
That's a heartwarming childhood memory.
讲真 只是其中的一件罢了
Hmm. One of the better ones, actually.
-确认受害者身份了吗  -还没
- Did you ID the victim. - Not yet.
他口袋里除了一些零钱 什么也没有
There was nothing in his pockets but some loose cash.
他们没把钱拿走
They didn't take the money
没
No.
有目击者吗
Any witnesses
昨晚出现在这儿的大部分现在都在外面要钱呢
Most of the people here last night are out panhandling now.
我寻访过的那些人 得到的答案普遍都是
People I did talk to, I believe the general consensus was--
滚你妈蛋 警探
"Go fuck yourself, Detective"
能加个“警探”都很不错了
I would've appreciated "Detective." Oh.
爸
有事吗
What do you want
首先 别挂电话
Not to be hung up on, for starters.
你不觉得有点任性了吗
That's a bit petulant, don't you think
爸 我很忙 有什么事啊
I'm busy, Dad. What do you want
我想让你回家
I want you to come home.
有要事
It's important.
是 没问题 我可以不管不顾抛下手头一切
Yeah, sure, I'll just...I'll just drop everything I'm doing
直接跳上第一班飞机往回赶呗
and hop on the first plane.
我时日无多 克莱尔
I'm dying, Claire.
胰腺癌
Pancreatic cancer.
医生说我随时都可能死
Doctors say I could go any time now.
我先得跟你说件事
There's something I need to tell you first.
现在再赔罪太晚了
It's too late to make amends.
跟皮特有关
It's about Peter.
皮特怎么了
What about Peter
你要不自己亲眼来看 是不会信我的
You won't believe me unless you see for yourself.
抱歉 先生 我们一小时后才开门
I'm sorry, sir. We don't open for about an hour.
不是 嗯
Oh. No. Yes. Uh...
我想问下 泽克在不在
I-I was just wondering if, uh, Zeke is in
在 请稍等
Yeah. Just a moment, please.
你好 有什么能帮到您的吗
Hi. Can I help you
嘿 兄弟
Hey, brother.
辛西娅
Cynthia....
能让我们单独谈谈吗
Can you give us a sec
这地方很棒啊
The place looks incredible.
艾莉诺 她还是
Is Eleanor...Is she still...
她还是跟之前一样 对
She's still the same. Yes.
很抱歉不打招呼
Look, I'm sorry to show up
就这么跑过来
out of the blue like this.
是这样 艾莉跟我回来了 然后
The thing is, Ellie and I are back in town, and, uh--
-你是需要钱吗  -不是 我需要份工作
And do you need money - No. I need a job.
我什么都能做
I'll do anything.
我可以去洗碗
I'll-I'll-I'll wash dishes,
倒垃圾
take out the garbage, anything.
你认真的
You're serious.
我需要你帮忙
I need your help.
我干嘛要帮你
And why would I ever help you
因为
It's...
丽兹会想让你帮我
what Liz would want.
要来吗
You coming
这是我们主厨 丹妮埃尔·威尔森
This is our head chef, Danielle Wilson.
丹妮埃尔 这位是
Danielle, this is--
马克
- Mark. - Uh...
马克来是
Uh, Mark here
给你打下手的
is gonna be staging for you today.
午市我很忙的
I have a lunch rush coming in.
没时间照顾你朋友
I don't have time to babysit your friend.
以前他是这里总厨
This used to be his kitchen.
很久以前的事了
That-that was a long time ago.
给他个机会证明自己吧
Just give him one shift to prove himself.
要是他不行 就直接走人
If he washes out, he's gone.
祝好运
Good luck.
你刀工怎么样
How's your knife skills
-你说什么  -你刀工好吗
- Sorry. - Are you good with a knife
好
Yes.
青葱切丁 要一夸脱
Brunoise a quart of shallots.
要是干得好 再说之后的
If you don't fuck it up, we'll keep talking.
我知道你不想跟我说话
I know you don't want to talk to me,
我就在这儿坐一小会儿
so I will just sit here for a bit.
等我站起来的时候
And when I get back up,
也许会记着把这个拿走
maybe I'll remember to take this with me.
也许不会
Maybe I won't.
昨晚 我正打算睡觉
Last night, I-I was trying to sleep,
就听到有人在叫
and I heard someone screaming.
我往外看 看到有个人从街上走过去
I look out, there's a guy coming down the street,
浑身是血
and he's covered in blood.
那人长什么样
What's the guy look like
白人 二十来岁
White, twenties,
运动衫 牛仔裤
sweatshirt and jeans.
大块头吗
Big guy
比你壮不了多少
Not much bigger than you.
但是 他的眼睛
But...his eyes...
他眼睛怎么了
What about his eyes
你有没有
You ever, um...
有没有 晚上拍照的时候 看到的不是眼睛
...you ever, like, take a photo at night, instead of eyes,
会看到那种小光环
you get these little rings of light
所以说那个小个子力气比得上熊
So a little guy with the strength of a bear
眼睛还能在夜里发光呗
and eyes that glow in the dark
我真看到了
I'm telling you what I saw.
你在这儿住多久了
How long you been using here
几个月吧
Couple months.
之前在这附近见过这人吗
You ever seen this guy around
他今早来找过我
He showed up this morning,
说他找到份工
talking about how he's got a job now.
-上次他说这话的时候  -其实是贩毒
- Last time he said that-- - He was dealing.
嗯
Yeah.
我以为的活动区域是上城
I thought his corner was uptown.
之前是 我
It was. I-I just--
我还以为他退出我儿子生活了呢
I also thought he was out of the picture.
我还能怎么着
Look, what am I supposed to do
以赛亚就跟瞧见圣诞树一样围着他爸转悠
Isaiah lights up like a Christmas tree around his dad.
他朋友也不是很多
It's not like that boy is flush with friends.
不许坐这 怪胎
Not there, freak.
继续
Keep going.
嘿 风衣挺帅啊
Hey. Cool trench coat.
准备才艺表演了吗
Doing anything for the talent show
失败者才参加才艺表演呢
Talent shows are for losers.
没错
Totally.
-想看点厉害的么  -靠
- Want to see something cool - Jesus Christ.
未知来信
你咋不去自杀啊 怪胎
"Shake It Out" by Kelly Clarkson
魔鬼在你背后
♪ Hard to dance ♪
让你难以舞动
♪ With a devil on your back ♪
把他甩掉
♪ So shake him off ♪
忘却邪念
♪ And I am done with my graceless heart ♪
今晚我将去除他 再重新出发
♪ So tonight I'm gonna cut it out and then restart ♪
因为想坚定自己的意志
♪ 'Cause I like to keep my issues drawn ♪
黎明前总是很黑暗
♪ It's always darkest before the dawn. ♪
尽情释放吧
♪ Shake it out ♪
♪ Shake it out, oh-whoa ♪
好了 主厨
Ready, Chef.
这是要干嘛啊 老人家 还给你颁个奖不成
What do you want, old man A medal
继续切
Keep going.
想着你可能想直接拿现金
Figured you'd want to be paid in cash.
明天九点上班
Tomorrow's shift starts at 9:00.
丹妮埃尔的评价是 宝刀未老
According to Danielle, you're not a total lost cause.
来 坐
Come on, grab a seat.
不了 我得回去陪艾莉了
Oh, no. I got to get back to Ellie.
坐下
Man, sit your ass down.
-不了 真的 我得走了  -我才给你份工作
- No, really. I got to go. - I just gave you a job.
别这么混蛋好吧
Don't be an asshole.
行
Yeah.
敬我的教女
To my goddaughter.
天 有没有
- Oh. - Oh, God-- See
跟凯瑟琳·特纳的声音一样有韵味
It's like drinking Kathleen Turner's voice.
我让他们给店里制作了一桶
I have 'em make a barrel for the restaurant
另外一整桶就供我自个儿喝
and a whole another one just for me.
-你还那样啊  -嗯
- Ah, you haven't changed. - Yeah.
也就胖了点吧
A little fatter, maybe.
女士们好像也不是很在意这点
Ladies don't seem to mind.
还单着呢吧
- Still a bachelor, I take it - Well,
我碰到过命定之人
I did meet the perfect woman,
可她嫁给我最好的哥们了
but she married my best friend instead.
为什么回来
Why are you back
你要是想在这里一直做下去
'Cause if you're gonna be in this restaurant,
我得清楚所有来龙去脉
I need to know what just walked in that door.
艾莉跟我没法在一个地方久留
Me and Ellie can't really stay in one place for long before--
因为她要吃东西
Before she needs a meal
我本想说因为别人会起疑
I-I was gonna say before people begin asking questions,
-我们就只能到处跑  -来这儿就不用跑了么
- and we have to run. - And that's different here
-也许吧  -为什么
- Maybe. - Yeah Why
因为这里发生了很多起凶杀案
Because of all the murders going on
警力都投入到这些案子上了
And while the police have their hands full with that,
所以你就能悄无声息的动手了呗
you can go about your business unnoticed
-等等 不是 就  -我天
- Just hold on. No, no, just-- - Oh, Jesus Christ.
-滚  -不
- Get the fuck out of here. - No, no, no, no, no.
-再别回来了  -听我解释
- And don't come back! - Let me explain.
我们说好的
We had a deal!
听着 我同意替艾莉诺
Listen, the only reason I agreed
保守秘密的唯一原因是因为你应承过
to keep Eleanor's secret was because you promised
会一直寻找解药
that you would never stop looking for a cure.
你他妈以为我们这是在干嘛呢
What the fuck do you think we've been doing
我们所有地方都去过了
We've been everywhere!
加拿大那边发生了几起凶杀案
There were these murders up in Canada.
尸体的血被抽干了
Bodies drained of blood.
自打我听说这事之后 就收拾行李过去了
Since I heard of that, we packed our bags and went,
以为这回一定是
thinking that this has to be
什么都不是
There was nothing.
就是某个喜欢
It was just some sick asshole
保存受害者尸体的变态
who liked to preserve his victims' bodies.
后来
And-and later on,
我听说凶手在受害者身上留下了咬痕
I heard about a killer who left bite marks on his victims.
于是又一次 我们收拾行李过去
And again, we packed and went.
同样的 一无所获
And again, nothing.
然后就不断的重复着
And then again and again and again.
每次 我都跟艾莉保证说
And every time, I promise Ellie,
亲爱的 这回不一样
"Honey, this time, it's different.
这回 我们会找到把你弄成这样的
This time we will find the monster
那个怪物
that did this to you,
我们会找到解药的
and that will lead us to a cure."
每次她都寄予厚望
And every time I would bring her hopes high,
然后铩羽而归
and then shatter them to pieces.
我很想帮忙
I want to help,
但留你在这里工作的话 会给我的员工
but just having you here puts everyone who works for me--
我的家人 带来危险
my family-- at risk.
我没法留你在这儿
And I can't do that
只为了你能有个掩护的身份
just so you can have cover while you--
不 不只是 听我说
No, that's not the only-- That's-- Listen to me.
我们回来不只是因为这个
That's not the only reason why we're back.
发生在市中心的这些凶杀案
These murders in Midtown,
每起案子都是夜里发生的
every one of them happened at night,
杀戮的性质
and the nature of the killings...
野蛮程度
There's a savagery--
你是说 你觉得凶手是
You're saying that you think the killer's a--
不是 我不知道
No. I-I don't know.
就艾莉而言
And as far as Ellie knows,
我们回来的唯一原因
the only reason we're back
就是不再
is to stop...
奔波
running.
过去的十年 就是噩梦
It's been a nightmare, the last ten years.
她值得过的更好
She deserves better.
她理应过上正常人的生活
She deserves something resembling a life.
日落 下午4:28
你好
Hello
你还好吗
Are you okay
你没穿鞋
You're not wearing shoes.
不冷吗
Aren't you cold
我感觉不到冷
I don't get cold.
怎么会
How come
应该是不记得什么叫冷了吧
I guess I've forgotten how.
你住这边吗
Do you live here
我住你隔壁
I live next door to you.
你怎么知道我住哪儿的
How do you know where I live
是你肚子在叫吗
Was that you
你肯定很饿了
You must be really hungry.
是的
I am.
给
Here.
想吃的话都给你
You can have it if you want.
我本打算留着以后吃的
I was saving it for later.
我吃不了巧克力
I can't eat chocolate.
真的吗
Seriously
我要吃不了巧克力 都不知道该怎么办了
I don't know what I would do if I couldn't eat chocolate.
我超爱巧克力的
I love chocolate.
你可以 替我吃
You could...eat it for me.
什么
What
你吃 我看着
You could eat, and I could watch.
感觉怪怪的
That's weird.
你说的对 那算了
You're right. Forget it.
别
No.
就
It's...
我不介意
I don't mind.
好吃吧
It's good, huh
我天
Oh, my God.
好好吃
It's so good.
亲爱的
Sweetheart
嗨 马克先生
Hi, Mr. Mark.
我得走了谢谢你的巧克力
I got to go. Thanks for the chocolate.
有事吗
Can I help you
是 我 我想为我儿子找样东西
Yeah. I'm-I'm looking for something for my son.
-生日吗  -什么
- Birthday - Sorry
是特殊场合要用的吗
Is it a special occasion
我今早对他态度特别差劲
I was an asshole this morning.
-他多大了  -12
- How old is he - Twelve.
我刚想猜是12
I was gonna guess that.
而且他 他总被人取笑
And he, um...he gets picked on,
所以如果得想办法让他
so if we could avoid anything that's gonna make--
你是说摆脱被人取笑的局面对吧
You're saying to steer clear of the never-ending scarf.
我有个正合适的
I have just the thing.
我 我应该
Oh, I-I should've...Uh...
他更喜欢硬币啊纸牌啊之类的
He's more into the, uh, coins and cards.
相信我 这个
Trust me, this...
会把他们班同学
is gonna freak...
震翻的
his classmates out.
我 我觉得他可能
Yeah, I-I just don't think he's really
不会
trying to-- Oh.
哇 这也太
Okay. Wow. That is, uh--
-逼真了吧  -我知道
So real. I know.
即便是大人都搞不明白怎么弄的
Even the grown-ups can't figure out how it's done.
那不 那不是
Well, isn't...isn't that just a, uh...
就是针里面伸缩泵 然后你胳膊上有橡皮胶浆
a pump in the needle and some rubber glue on your arm
而且 被针刺伤后
Also, that's not... that's not really the way
不是那样流血的 还有血的颜色
a puncture wound bleeds, and the...and the color
其实挺假的
of the blood isn't real...
-抱歉  -那么
- Sorry. - So,
硬币和纸牌哈
cards and coins
对 对 他喜欢
Yeah, yeah. He likes, um,
放在手掌心
palm of the hand,
东西可以不见然后再回来那种
make things vanish and-and reappear.
怎么了
What
我觉得他可能会喜欢这个
I suspect he'll like this.
等等 你为什么哼了一声
Now, wait. Just, um, why'd you go, "Hmm"
你儿子喜欢玩的那套
The magic your son is doing,
其实挺复杂的
it's pretty sophisticated.
甚至过于精巧
Delicate, even.
很少有12岁的小孩懂得欣赏
Qualities rarely appreciated by 12-year-old boys.
如果你想让他交点朋友
If you want him to make friends,
这个针就最合适了
I'd get him the needle instead.
-说吧  -说什么
- Just say it, okay - What
你很明显不喜欢我跟那个男生说话
You clearly don't like that I was talking to that boy.
我一直都特别希望
I want nothing more than for you
能有个除了我之外的人陪你说说话
to have someone to talk to besides me.
但你得小心点
You just have to be careful, that's it.
我都没告诉他我叫什么
I didn't even tell him my name.
你担心的不是我
You're not worried about me.
你担心的是我会把他怎么样
You're worried I'd do something to him.
真酷是不是
It's cool, huh
-还行  -别装了
- It's okay. - Oh, come on.
就是还行
It's okay.
星系就像是
Galaxies are like islands
太空海中的岛屿
in the sea of space.
它们发出数十亿太阳的光芒
They glow with the light of billions of suns.
哈勃望远镜精细地揭示了
The Hubble telescope reveals nearby galaxies
附近星系的细节
in exquisite detail.
像这样的星系充斥着整个宇宙
Galaxies like these fill the universe.
它们的光需要数十亿年才能到达我们这里
It takes billions of years for their light to reach us.
我们看到的不是它们现在的样子 而是它们过去的样子
We see them not as they are but as they once were.
嗨
Hello
在厨房呢 亲爱的
The kitchen, baby.
这里还好吗
What's going on in here
工作怎么样
- Okay. - How was work
挺好
Good.
-是哈勃望远镜上看到的吗  -嗯嗯
- Is that from Hubble - Mm-hmm.
你没事吧
You okay
没事
Yeah.
你还好吗
You good
-我们得回家了  -就是肚子里有气
- We got to get you home. - It was just a pang.
艾莉诺
Eleanor.
我扛到明天都没事 我保证
I'll be fine till tomorrow, I promise.
别毁了今晚的愉快时光 好吗
Let's not ruin tonight, okay
接下来你想去哪
Where would you like to go next
怎么了
What
好了 海岸安全了
All right. Coast is clear.
待那别动
Stay there!
靠
Fuck.
见鬼
Shit!
-爸爸帮忙  -艾莉
- Dad, help! - Ellie!
我来对付他
I'll get him.
你为什么要检查尖牙
Why are you checking for fangs
-这没道理  -为什么
- Doesn't make any sense. - Why
-你是在检查尖牙吗  -看见他的眼睛了吗
- are you checking for fangs - See his eyes
看他的眼睛
Look at his eyes.
看它们发出来的光了吗
See how they're glowing
那是因为你用手电筒照着他的眼睛
Because you just shined a light in his eyes.
他跟你一样强壮
He was strong like you.
你看到咬痕了吗
Do you see a bite mark
没
No.
他试图喝你的血了吗
Did he try and drink your blood
-没  -因为他跟我不一样
No. Because he's not like me.
你说过我们不再这样了
You told me we were done with this.
还有多久他会醒
How long till he wakes up
20分钟 也许更短
20 minutes. Maybe less.
那就别在再浪费时间了
We should stop wasting time.
我觉得我扛不到明天了 现在不行了
I don't think I can make it till tomorrow, not anymore.
好了
All right.
Okay.
怎么了
What's wrong
-他体内有东西  -什么
- He's on something. - What
我不知道 我从没喝过这种味道的
I don't know. It's nothing I've tasted before.
屏蔽号码
134街与12街 三十分钟
我建议咱们举起七喜
I would like us to raise our 7UPs
感谢你妈做的美味晚餐
and thank your mother for this fantastic meal.
美味谈不上吧
I don't know about fantastic.
你说啥
Excuse me.
嘿 你妈做这顿饭可费了不少劲
Hey, your mother worked very hard on this dinner.
要是能再加点盐就更好了
Although it wouldn't kill you to add a little salt.
我就知道
- I know, right
下次你来做
You are most welcome to cook next time.
咋了
What
你说下次
You said "next time."
未知号码
134街与12街 三十分钟
我们吃饭时不看手机的
We try not to have our phones at the table.
抱歉
Oh. Sorry.
我马上回来
I'll be back in a second.
我得走了 小家伙
I got to run, little man.
你有没有什么魔术要给我表演一下啊
You got any, uh, magic to show me before I go
实际上
Actually...
咋了
What
明天晚上学校有才艺表演
There's this talent show tomorrow night at school.
我本来不想去的 但如果你
I was gonna skip it, but if you--
几点
What time's the show
7点
- Seven. - Ah.
嘿 我有个硬币 你可以练习一下
Hey, I got a coin for you to practice with.
-爸 我硬币多了去了  -这个可是幸运币
- Dad, I have quarters. - No, but this one is lucky.
怎么幸运
How come
看看年份
Check out the year.
厉害吧
Boom.
再见了 大卫·布莱恩（大魔术师）
See you around, David Blaine.
你确定自己没受伤吗
You sure you're not hurt
没事 赶紧回家吧
I'm fine. Let's just go home.
好吧 一会我就回去哈
All right, look, I'm gonna meet you there, okay
怎么了
What
What's wrong
嘿 艾莉
Hey, Ellie. Hey.
我们今天本来过得好好的
We were having a good day.
我都不记得上次这样是什么时候了 然后你丢下我
I can't remember the last time we had. And then you leave me
-去追  -等会
- to chase down-- - Now, just hold on one second.
是你说的 我们要小心
You're the one who said we have to be careful.
说我们必须超级小心才能待在这
That we'll only get to stay here if we're super careful.
然后你就追人去了下水道
And then you go running into a freaking sewer
-还差点害死你自己  -好了 好了
- and almost get yourself killed. - Okay. Okay, okay.
你说的对 刚才我太鲁莽了 对不起
You're right. That was reckless, and I'm sorry.
你 你 你说的非常对
And-and-and you were absolutely right
那个人确实跟你不一样
when you said that man wasn't like you.
但是他的血液里有某种你从未尝过的药
But he was on some drug that you'd never tasted before.
听我说
Look, listen!
他吃的药让他跟你行为很像
Whatever he was on had him acting like you.
所以也许这里面有什么古怪
So maybe there's still something here.
我要吃东西
I need to eat.
我知道你觉得这恶心
I know that disgusts you, but--
不 我不觉得恶心
No, it doesn't disgust me.
-你就是  -我没有
- Yes, it does. - It doesn't!
我喝血时你都不敢看我
You can't even look at me when I feed.
不 艾莉 我现在没时间跟你争论这个
Nah, I don't have time for that shit right now, Ellie.
-我们得走了  -那也许
Come on, let's go. Then maybe
-我自己去找晚餐更合适  -不 不行
- I'll go find my own dinner. - That's-that...
你不能那么做
No, no. No, you-you're not gonna do that.
-为什么不行  -因为这是规矩
- Why not - 'Cause that's the rule.
-你不会那么做  -为什么不行
- You do not do that. - Why not !
因为你不是那种人
That's not who you are!
如果
What if it is
如果我早晚都会变成那样呢
What if this is all I'll ever be
不会的
It's not.
我保证 不会的
I promise it's not.
好吗
Okay-
回家去吧
Go home, please.
晚点家里见 好吗
I'll meet you there later, okay
我会给你带晚餐的
And I will bring you dinner.
去吧
Go.
晚上好 洛根医生 我叫马修
Evening, Dr. Logan. My name's Matthew.
你父亲在里面等你
Your father's waiting for you inside.
抱歉让你看到这种现状
You'll have to forgive the state of things.
诉讼堆积如山 你爸
After the lawsuits piled up, your dad was forced
只好把其它东西都卖了
to let the rest of his staff go.
可怜的家伙
Poor guy.
他让数百万人吃止痛药上瘾
Gets millions of people hooked on painkillers,
最后债台高筑一无所有 却留下了这栋海滨豪宅
and they take everything from him but his waterfront mansion.
也许等你年纪大点时
Well, perhaps as you get older,
才会经历更深刻 更剧烈的疼痛
you'll experience pain in a more profound and acute way.
到时你就不会觉得
And you won't find
改善疼痛症状有什么可鄙的了
its amelioration such an ignoble pursuit.
谢谢你 马修
Thank you, Matthew.
欢迎回家
Welcome home.
这里不是我家
This isn't my home.
遗嘱里我把这留给你了
Well, I left it to you in my will.
你说要告诉我皮特的事
You had something to tell me about Peter
你感觉如何 爸爸
"How are you feeling, Dad
我能为你做点什么吗
Is there anything I can do for you"
根本没有什么皮特 对吗
You don't, do you
-自私如你  -你当然要打着皮特的幌子
- Selfish as always. - Of course you'd bait me here
才能把我骗过来 你想用豪宅收买我
with Peter, when really all you want to do
让我宽恕你
is buy back my forgiveness.
看得出来你依然坚持认为
Oh. I see we're still clinging
这个糟糕的父亲
to the narrative I was a terrible father.
哦不 你是最棒的父亲
Uh, no, you were fantastic.
你和皮特一无所有
You and Peter wanted for nothing.
记得妈妈走后你对我们说了什么吗
Do you remember what you told us after Mom took off
记得吗
Do you
你说 你俩降生之前 她一直都很开心
You said, "She was always happy till you two came around."
是我养大了皮特
I raised Peter,
在你忙着让博物馆为你冠名时
while you were off having some museum named in your honor.
是我在辅导他做家庭作业
I was the one helping him with his homework,
哄他睡觉 培养他上学
putting him to bed, putting off college.
等我终于离开了这个家
And when I finally went,
我连大一都没念完 就接到了你的电话
I hadn't even finished my freshman year when you called
说你带着他去打猎
to tell me you'd taken him hunting.
却让他误入了母熊和小熊的缠斗
And he'd somehow come between a mother bear and her cub.
等我回来参加葬礼的时候
And when I came home for the funeral...
他的棺材才刚入土
his casket had barely been put in the ground
你扭过头对我说
when you turned to me and you said,
你差不多也该回学校了
"I guess you should be getting back to school."
所以你没说错
So you're right.
你真是世界上最好的老爸
You were Father of the Fucking Year.
我祝你死得愉快
Have a nice death.
我从没带皮特去打猎
I never took Peter hunting.
袭击他的
And what attacked him...
也不是熊
it wasn't a bear.
我把这座房子给你
I'm not leaving you this house
不是为了洗刷自己的内疚
to buy back my guilt.
我要你继续我的事业
I need you to continue my work.
10年来 我一直在寻找
For ten years, I have been trying
治愈良方
to develop a cure,
我马上就要成功了
and I am so close.
治愈什么的良方
A cure for what
你弟弟
For your brother.
你究竟在说什么呀
What the fuck are you talking about
我不能跟你聊天 我在练习魔术手法
I can't really talk. I need to work on my routine.
哦 那正好 给你买了个小礼物
Hey, speaking of, I got you something.
你去了塔南家
You went to Tannen's!
真棒 谢谢
Oh. Cool, thanks.
里面不光这一个
Um, that's not all that's in there.
不会吧 你知道这是什么吗
No way. Do you even know what this is
我只希望自己不是买了个空袋子呢
I was just hoping I didn't pay for an empty bag.
你想跟给我展示一下吗
You want to show me how it works
你根本不喜欢魔术
You don't like magic.
-那 那倒不是  -嘿
- That-That's not true. - Hey,
在院子里看到几个小朋友
I saw some kids out in the courtyard.
可以给变给他们看吗
Maybe I can show them
我知道你不想让我成为
I know you don't want me to make myself
众人的目标 我觉得至少我可以
an easy target. I just thought maybe
亲爱的 亲爱的
- I could at least try-- - Sweetheart. Sweetheart.
听我说
Listen.
你看
Look.
如果这个世界很太平
If the world were good,
你可以想穿什么就穿什么
you could...you could wear whatever you want
想怎么样就怎么样
and be exactly who you are.
如果我会变魔术
And if I could do a magic trick,
我会把这个世界变得更喜欢你
it'd be to make the world more like you.
让这个世界配得上你
Make it worthy of you.
这个世界
The world's...
我只是不想让你出事儿
I just want you safe.
我明白
I got it.
就在院子里玩 不许出去
No further than the courtyard.
9:00就熄灯了
Lights out by 9:00.
谢谢妈妈
Thanks, Mom.
艾莉
我很饿 请快点
嘿 各位 咋样啊
Hi, guys. How's it hanging
你们听到他在说什么了吗
Did y'all hear something
-没有 你呢  -没
- No. Did you - No.
想不想去玩游戏机
You want to play some Xbox
当然了 我要第一个玩
Hell yeah, and I get first player.
嘿 咋样啊
How's it hanging
我是说 你还好吗
I mean, how's it going
我给你看个东西如何
Can I show you something real quick
但你要走近一点
But you got to come close.
这只是因一枚普通的硬币 对吧
Just a regular quarter, right
怎么回事啊
I don't get it.
好吧
Well...
这叫魔法
It's magic.
什么
What
你的眼睛怎么了
What's with your eyes
好酷啊 你怎么把眼睛变成这样的
That's so cool. How do you make 'em do that
用魔法啊
With magic.
我该走了
I should go.
顺便说下 我叫以赛亚
I'm Isaiah, by the way.
我叫艾莉诺
I'm Eleanor.
打扰下 你好
Excuse me. Hi.
有什么事吗
Can I help you
呃 对
Uh, yeah. Um,
我对你卖的东西很感兴趣
I'm interested in what-what you're selling.
为什么
What would that be
我听说市面上有一种新货
I heard there's something new out there
效果挺强劲的
Something strong
别别别 等等我
No, no, no. Wait, wait, wait. Wait.
我有钱 我不是警察
I have money. Look, I'm not a cop.
祝你今晚过得愉快
You have yourself a nice night.
-不不不 等一下  -别烦我了
- No, no, no, no. Just wait. - We're done here.
我要问你几个问题
I'm gonna ask you some questions,
如果你老实交代
and if you're honest with me,
也许有希望
there's a chance
活着从这里走出去
you walk out of here alive.
你懂吗
Do you understand
这是我在你外套口袋里找到的
I found these in your jacket pocket.
这是什么
What is it
我不知道
I-I don't know.
不 你别激动 我发誓我真的不知道
No, no. Just-just take it easy. I swear, I-I don't know.
我可以全都告诉你
Look, I-I'll tell you everything.
但请你冷静 好吗
Just-just be cool, okay Um...
几周之前我出门去参加
A couple weeks ago, I was...I was...
戒断互助会
I was coming out of an AA meeting,
有个人问我想不想赚点钱
and this guy asked me if I wanted to make some money.
他每天晚上会给我发个地址
Every night, he texts me an address.
我过去 他把货给我
I go there, he gives me product to sell.
第二天晚上 又有一个新的地址
The next night, it's a new address.
我把钱给这个人 他会给我重新填货
I go give the man his money, he gives me more product to sell.
-那人叫什么  -我不知道啊
- What is the man's name - I-I don't know.
-电话多少  -我不知道
- What's his number - I don't know.
我对天发誓真的不知道
I swear to Christ, I don't know, okay
他也是个中间人 但他提到过一个女的
Look, h-he's just a middleman, but I heard him talking
这个生意背后是她在负责
about some woman who is in charge of this whole thing.
-什么女人  -我真他妈不知道
What woman - I-I don't fucking know.
你说了半天一点有价值的都没有
You are not giving me anything useful,
-这对你很不利  -听我说
- and that is not good for you. Okay, listen, listen.
我外套口袋里有一部手机
In my jacket pocket, there's a phone.
我的上家
The guy that I work for--
他明晚会短信告诉我一个新地址
he will text me tomorrow with a new address.
要是想找这个人 他明天晚上会在那里
If you want to find this dude, he will be there tomorrow.
这种药你了解多少
What do you know about this drug
很少
Not much.
买药的人说 这种药提供了一种原始快感
Uh, the people who buy it say that-that it's a primal high.
吃了后感觉自己能飞檐走壁 只不过
It makes 'em feel like they can run through walls, except--
只不过什么
Except what
很显然 醒药的过程很痛苦
Apparently, the hangover's brutal.
是一种什么感觉呢
Makes them feel like.
就像是走在阳光下 皮肤都在
When they go out in the sun, it makes them feel like
燃烧的感觉
their skin is on fire.
还有呢
W-What else
我只知道这么多了
That's all I know.
你自己有吃过吗
You ever used it yourself
-当然没有  -别撒谎
- No way. - Don't lie to me!
-我没撒谎  -你要是没戒干净
- I'm not lying. - If you are not clean,
必须现在告诉我
you have to say it now.
你看看我的口袋 好吗
Look in my pocket, okay
我裤子口袋 看一眼
My pants pocket, look inside, okay
好的 好的
Okay. Okay. Shh.
清醒三个月了
See Three months.
我连酒都没喝过 更别说吸毒了 我戒干净了
I haven't had a drink, much less a drug. I am clean.
我也不想参与这种勾当 只是
Didn't mean to get mixed up in this shit, man. I just...
我有个儿子
I just have a...I have a son.
我不想听你家的事
I-I don't want to hear about your family.
对 我只想赚点钱 我都没有
Yeah, I'm try-trying to make some money, and I can't
-带他们出去吃饭的钱  -我不想听
- even take 'em to dinner. - I don't want to hear about it.
-我连公寓都付不起  -别告诉我
- I can't get an apartment. - Please stop that!
别让我说第二遍
I'm not gonna say it again!
你有孩子吗
Do you have a kid
有的话 你就会懂
Then you know.
你懂
You know.
我儿子就是我黑暗中的希望
That boy is my light in the dark.
我还想再见到我儿子
And I want to see him again.
我很抱歉
And I am so sorry
卷进这种勾当中
that I got mixed up in all this mess, man.
我只想让我孩子过得更好
I'm-I'm just trying to take care of my kid.
我也是
- So am I.
这边走
This way.
我把他从阳光下拉了出来 救了他一命
I pulled him out of the sun before it was too late.
做好心理准备 他的样子很惨
You should brace yourself for what you're about to see.
克莱尔
Claire
真的是你吗
Is that really you
对
Yeah.
是的
皮特
Pete.
我来了
I'm here.
想不到你来了
I can't believe it's you.
你看起来那么
You look so...
怎么了
What
长大了
Grown-up.
"Sweet Child O' Mine" by Guns N' Roses
她的笑容对我来说
♪ She's got a smile that it seems to me ♪
能勾起童年的回忆
♪ Reminds me of childhood memories ♪
当时的一切都那么新鲜
♪ Where everything was as fresh ♪
如同蓝天般明快
♪ As the bright blue sky ♪
我偶尔会看看她的脸
♪ Now and then when I see her face ♪
体会那种特别的感觉
♪ She takes me away to that special place ♪
如果我盯着她看太久
♪ And if I stare too long ♪
可能会崩溃 大哭一场
♪ I'd probably break down and cry ♪
我可爱的孩子
♪ Sweet child o' mine ♪